<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Factions on Divide and Conquer: AI and Gameplay Overhaul</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/</link><description>Recent content in Factions on Divide and Conquer: AI and Gameplay Overhaul</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anduin Vale</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/anduin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/anduin/</guid><description>Description [Home] of many sturdy men, and to their land between the Mountains and Mirkwood neither orc nor wolf dared to go. &amp;ldquo;Indeed,&amp;rdquo; said Glóin, &amp;ldquo;if it were not for the Beornings, the passage from Dale to Rivendell would long ago have become impossible. They are valiant men and keep open the High Pass and the Ford of Carrock. But their tolls are high,&amp;rdquo; he added with a shake of his head; &amp;ldquo;and like Beorn of old they are not over fond of dwarves.</description></item><item><title>Ar-Adûnâim</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/adunaim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/adunaim/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;The great cape and land-locked firth of Umbar had been Númenórean land since days of old; but it was a stronghold of the King&amp;rsquo;s Men, who were afterwards called the Black Númenóreans, corrupted by Sauron, and who hated above all the followers of Elendil. After the fall of Sauron their race swiftly dwindled or became merged with the Men of Middle-earth, but they inherited without lessening their hatred of Gondor.</description></item><item><title>Bree-land</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/bree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/bree/</guid><description>Description Some will tell you that Bree is old.
Older than the Shire. Older than Minas Tirith. Older than Fornost. Older than the Havens. They tell that there has been a settlement here, on the Road, since the First Age of the World. And the Road passing through the Bree-land is ancient, for it was made by the Firstborn, long, long ago, when they passed this way heading West.</description></item><item><title>Clans of Enedwaith</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/enedwaith/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/enedwaith/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;A fairly numerous but barbarous fisher-folk dwelt between the mouths of the Gwathló and the Angren&amp;hellip; tribes of &amp;lsquo;Wild Men&amp;rsquo;, fishers and fowlers, on the coasts of Enedwaith, who were akin in race and speech to Drúedain of Anórien.&amp;rdquo; - Little known background of the clans
Campaign Features The Great Clanmoot Early into the campaign, the Clans of Enedwaith will call a Great Clanmoot and decide the fate of their people.</description></item><item><title>Dol Guldur</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dolguldur/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dolguldur/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;There lies the fastness of Southern Mirkwood,&amp;rsquo; said Haldir. &amp;lsquo;It is clad in a forest of dark fir, where the trees strive one against another and their branches rot and wither. In the midst upon a stony height stands Dol Guldur, where long the hidden Enemy had his dwelling. We fear that now it is inhabited again, and with power sevenfold. A black cloud lies often over it of late.</description></item><item><title>Dominion of Isengard</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/isengard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/isengard/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;I think that I now understand what he is up to. He is plotting to become a Power. He has a mind of metal and wheels; and he does not care for growing things, except as far as they serve him for the moment. And now it is clear that he is a black traitor. He has taken up with foul folk, with the Orcs. &amp;hellip; Worse than that: he has been doing something to them; something dangerous.</description></item><item><title>Dorwinion</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dorwinion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dorwinion/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;The heady vintage of the great gardens of Dorwinion&amp;hellip; a land of vines in &amp;rsquo;the burning South.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; - Little known information on Dorwinion
The land of Dorwinion has always fascinated its many visitors. It has been described as a most beautiful flower, captivating the eye and soul alike. Smooth hills, bountiful earth and rich grapevines that grow in abundance. It is said that if a seed is planted in Dorwinion&amp;rsquo;s soil, it will bloom thrice as plentiful as anywhere else.</description></item><item><title>Dunlendings</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dunland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dunland/</guid><description>Description In times long past and ill-remembered, shrouded in legend and mystery, the black tower was ruled by the Númenóreans. Today, it is held by the Wise One. Saruman. He sends us greetings, and gifts of blade and shield to our Gurach&amp;rsquo;s hall. He wishes to be our friend, so his emissaries claim, and sees the great injustices done to us by the Forgoil as debt in dire need of repayment.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves of Erebor</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/erebor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/erebor/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Under the Mountain dark and tall, The King has come unto his hall! His foe is dead, the Worm of Dread, And ever so his foes shall fall! The sword is sharp, the spear is long, The arrow swift, the Gate is strong. The heart is bold that looks on gold; The dwarves no more shall suffer wrong&amp;hellip; Now call we over the mountains cold, Come back unto the caverns old!</description></item><item><title>Dwarves of Ered Luin</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/eredluin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/eredluin/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;But a small dark figure that none had observed sprang out of the shadows and gave a hoarse shout: Baruk Khazâd! Khazâd ai-mênu! An axe swung and swept back. Two Orcs fell headless. The rest fled.&amp;rdquo; - Dwarven battle cry
Campaign Features Dwarven Relics Reclaim ancient Dwarven relics that rightfully belong to you using diplomacy, espionage or force Dwarven Rings of Power Decide the fate of the remaining Dwarves in Ered Luin.</description></item><item><title>Dwarves of Khazad-dûm</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/khazaddum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/khazaddum/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;The light of the shaft fell directly on a table in the middle of the room: a single oblong block, about two feet high, upon which was laid a great slab of white stone. &amp;hellip; On the slab runes were deeply graven&amp;hellip;. BALIN SON OF FUNDIN, LORD OF MORIA.&amp;rsquo; The Company stood silent beside the tomb of Balin. Frodo thought of Bilbo and his long friendship with the dwarf, and of Balin&amp;rsquo;s visit to the Shire long ago.</description></item><item><title>Easterlings of Rhûn</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/rhun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/rhun/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;The Easterlings were strong and war-hardened and asked for no quarter&amp;hellip; In the meanwhile the Wainriders plotted their revenge. Beyond the reach of the arms of Gondor in lands east of the Sea of Rhûn from which no tidings came to its Kings, their kinsfolk spread and multiplied, and they were eager for conquests and booty and filled with hatred of Gondor which stood in their way. It was long, however, before they moved&amp;rdquo; - Easterlings hatred</description></item><item><title>Goblins of Moria</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/moria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/moria/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Clap! Snap! the black crack! Grip, grab! Pinch, nab! And down, down to Goblin-town You go, my lad! Clash, crash! Crush, smash! Hammer and tongs! Knocker and gongs! Pound, pound, far underground! Ho, ho! my lad! Swish, smack! Whip crack! Batter and beat! Yammer and bleat! Work, work! Nor dare to shirk, While Goblins quaff, and Goblins laugh, Round and round far underground Below, my lad!&amp;rdquo; - Goblin prisoner song</description></item><item><title>Haradrim Tribes</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/harad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/harad/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;The Haradrim, a great and cruel people that dwelt in the wide lands south of Mordor beyond the mouths of Anduin&amp;hellip;. a grim folk, and not easily daunted by shade or blade. Out of Far Harad black men like half-trolls with white eyes and red tongues.&amp;rdquo; - Little known information on Harad
Campaign Features Unite the Clans Rise from the glittering city of Faen&amp;rsquo;obel and assert your control over the various tribes of Harad.</description></item><item><title>High Elves</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/highelves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/highelves/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;In all the days of the Third Age, after the fall of Gil-galad, Master Elrond abode in Imladris, and he gathered there many Elves, and other folk of wisdom and power from among all the kindred of Middle-earth, and he preserved through many lives of Men the memory of all that had been fair; and the house of Elrond was a refuge for the weary and the oppressed, and a treasury of good counsel and wise lore.</description></item><item><title>Kingdom of Dale</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dale/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;But there was still a company of archers that held their ground among the burning houses. Their captain was Bard, grim-voiced and grim-faced, whose friends &amp;hellip; knew his worth and courage. He was a descendant in long line of Girion, Lord of Dale, whose wife and child had escaped down the Running River from the ruin long ago. &amp;hellip; Bard took the lead [after the attack on Laketown], and ordered things as he wished, &amp;hellip; he had a hard task to govern the people and direct the preparations for their protection and housing.</description></item><item><title>Kingdom of Gondor</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/gondor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/gondor/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Believe not that in the land of Gondor the blood of Númenor is spent, nor all its pride and dignity forgotten. By our valour the wild folk of the East are still restrained, and the terror of Morgul kept at bay; and thus alone are peace and freedom maintained in the lands behind us, bulwark of the West. But if the passages of the River should be won, what then?</description></item><item><title>Kingdom of Rohan</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/rohan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/rohan/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Arise, arise, Riders of Théoden! Fell deeds awake: fire and slaughter! Spears shall be shaken, Shields shall be splintered, a sword-day, a red day, ere the sun rises! Ride now, ride now! Ride to Gondor! Death! Death! Death! Forth Eorlingas!&amp;rdquo; - Théoden&amp;rsquo;s war cry
Campaign Features Beacons of Gondor Light the Beacons of Rohan and recieve aid from Gondor Theoden&amp;rsquo;s Spell Dispel Grima from your court and release Theoden from his spell so he can exact his revenge on Saruman for his trickery and deceit Glittering Caves Restore the Glittering Caves of Helm&amp;rsquo;s Deep and cultivate a new home for lost Dwarves Gallery Units Sons of Eorl Soldiers 15 Melee Attack 9 Secondary Attack 9 Charge Bonus 15 Weapon Type Melee Total Defense 28 Armour 14 Defence Skill 9 Shield 5 Hitpoints 1 Recruitment Cost 1000 Upkeep 0 Bodyguard Unit Yes These men represent the military elite of Rohan, hand-picked by the King himself from amongst the most promising warriors of the kingdom.</description></item><item><title>Mordor</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/mordor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/mordor/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Ash nazg durbatulûk, ash nazg gimbatul, Ash nazg thrakatulûk! agh burzum-ishi krimpatul.&amp;rdquo; - Ring inscription
Campaign Features The One Ring (V3)
Send out your spies and the Nazgûl to find and return the One Ring. Bring Middle-earth to it&amp;rsquo;s knees. Rule them all.. Shadow of the East
If you maintain your alliances with Khand, Rhûn and Harad, you have the oppurtunity to recruit some of their better units. The Nine Nazgûl</description></item><item><title>Orcs of Gundabad</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/gundabad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/gundabad/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;In the Dwarvish traditions of the Third Age the names of the places where each of the Seven Ancestors had &amp;lsquo;awakened&amp;rsquo; were remembered &amp;hellip; that of the ancestor of the Longbeards [Durin&amp;rsquo;s Folk] &amp;hellip; had been Mount Gundabad (in origin a Khuzdul name), which was therefore revered by the Dwarves, and its occupation in the Third Age by the Orcs of Sauron was one of the chief reasons for their great hatred of the Orcs.</description></item><item><title>Principality of Dol Amroth</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dolamroth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dolamroth/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;[With Gandalf] went the Prince of Dol Amroth in his shining mail. For he and his knights still held themselves like lords in whom the race of Númenor ran true. Men that saw them whispered saying: &amp;lsquo;Be like the old tales speak well; there is Elvish blood in the veins of that folk, for the people of Nimrodel dwelt in that land once long ago.&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;. And last and proudest, [came] Imrahil, Prince of Dol Amroth, kinsman of the Lord, with gilded banners bearing his token of the Ship and the Silver Swan, and a company of knights in full harness riding grey horses; and behind them seven hundreds of men at arms, tall as lords, grey-eyed, dark-haired, singing as they came&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>Rangers of the North</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dunedain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/dunedain/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Few now remember them,&amp;rsquo; Tom murmured, &amp;lsquo;yet still some go wandering, sons of forgotten kings walking in loneliness, guarding from evil things folk that are heedless.&amp;rsquo; In those days no other Men had settled dwellings so far west, or within a hundred leagues of the Shire. But in the wild lands beyond Bree there were mysterious wanderers. The Bree-folk called them Rangers, and knew nothing of their origin. They were taller and darker than the Men of Bree and were believed to have strange powers of sight and hearing, and to understand the languages of beasts and birds.</description></item><item><title>Realm of Lothlórien</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/lorien/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/lorien/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;It seemed to him that he had stepped through a high window that looked on a vanished world. A light was upon it for which his language had no name. All that he saw was shapely, but the shapes seemed at once clear cut, as if they had been first conceived and drawn at the uncovering of his eyes, and ancient as if they had endured for ever. He saw no colour but those he knew, gold and white and blue and green, but they were fresh and poignant, as if he had at that moment first perceived them and made for them names new and wonderful.</description></item><item><title>Variags of Khand</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/khand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/khand/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Many of the Wainriders now passed south of Mordor and made alliance with men of Khand and of Near Harad; and in this great assault from north and south, Gondor came near to destruction.&amp;rdquo; - Khand&amp;rsquo;s history with Gondor and its neighbours
Campaign Features Blue Wizards Heed the advice of the Blue Wizards and resist Sauron, at the risk of all out civil war and his great Inquisitors or stand with him and refute the foreign wizards and their allies Gallery Units Variag Nobles Soldiers 20 Ranged Attack 6 Secondary Attack 8 Charge Bonus 5 Weapon Type Missile Total Defense 21 Armour 12 Defence Skill 9 Shield 0 Hitpoints 1 Recruitment Cost 1000 Upkeep 0 Bodyguard Unit Yes Khand is a land of tribes and chieftains, greatest of these are the Variags.</description></item><item><title>Witch-Realm of Angmar</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/angmar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/angmar/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;The Black Rider flung back his hood, and behold! he had a kingly crown; and yet upon no head visible was it set. The red fires shone between it and the mantled shoulders vast and dark. From a mouth unseen there came a deadly laughter. &amp;ldquo;Old fool!&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;Old fool! This is my hour. Do you not know Death when you see it? Die now and curse in vain!</description></item><item><title>Woodland Realm</title><link>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/woodlandrealm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.divide-and-conquer-ago.com/factions/woodlandrealm/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Now of old the name of that forest was Greenwood the Great, and its wide halls and aisles were the haunt of many beasts and of birds of bright song; and there was the realm of King Thranduil under the oak and the beech. But after many years, when well nigh a third of that age of the world had passed, a darkness crept slowly through the wood from the southward, and fear walked there in shadowy glades; fell beasts came hunting, and cruel and evil creatures laid there their snares.</description></item></channel></rss>